本影音版权属其出版、发行方，字幕制作仅供学术交流之用 请于下载后24小时内删除，并不得有公开传播或作商业盈利之行为 若有违法等相关行为，诸神字幕组恕不承担任何法律或连带责任。
翻译 koki  放 晴  La Fatalité
This Book is still incomplete.
まだまだの「本」ですが
お口に合いますかどうか
I wonder if it'll be to your liking.
压制 暗之亚瑟王  校对 凉YAN Lucifer 时间 Lucifer
Humans are difficult creatures.
人間というのは　どうも難しい生き物でしてね
All they seek is happiness,
幸せだけしか求めていないのに
but for some reason, they can't get it.
なぜか手に入らない
I'm sorry. I'm sure you know all this already.
いいえ　こんなこと言うまでもなく知っていますか
あなたなら
Mokkania... Feekiee...
モッカニア　フィーキー　ルイモン　キャスマ
Luimon... Casma...
疲れてるな　マットアラスト
You're exhausted, Mattalast.
Hamy's been sending you on too many jobs.
ハミのやつ　俺に仕事回しすぎだぜ
止まる者　愚かなりし
Todomaru mono oroka narishi
はらりひらり指に触れた黒い翼の　一片
Harari hirari yubi ni fureta
kuroi tsubasa no hitohira
诸
神&动漫国
君が一つの　物語なら
Kimi ga hitotsu no monogatari nara
まだいくらでも　掛け替えられる
Mada ikura demo kakikaerareru
血のインクは乾かない
Chi no inku wa kawakanai
誰も知らない　本との僕ら
Dare mo shiranai hontou no bokura
荒れた世界　枯れるのは
Areta sekai kaeru no wa
追い求めたのは　ちっぽけな幸福なんかじゃない
Oimotometa no wa
Chippoke na koufuku nanka ja nai
戦え　轟く　音を合図に
Tatakae todoroku kodou wo aizu ni
意のまま　進めば
Inomama susumeba yukusaki hatenai
行く先　果てない
抗え　のたうち
Aragae notauchi ikudo to yaburedo
幾度と　汚れと
Kizamou matotta kizuato ni yume wo
膝を纏った傷跡に夢を
埋もれそうな今日の記憶繋げるために　明日へ
Umoresou na kyo no kioku
tsunageru tame ni ashita e
Episode 16
A Banned Book, a Coward, and the Sacred Eyes
第16话 禁书
Damn it!
くそ
Minth, how much do you
think we'll get for these?
ミンス　これ売ったらいくらになる？
Tough to say...
さーな
一万といったところか
I'd estimate 10,000.
Hey. Wanna take it and run?
な　二人でこれ持て逃げないか
Not for 10,000.
持ち逃げするほどの金じゃないぞ
How long are we gonna stay
in the thievery business?
いつまでもこんな盗賊なんて続けてどうする
手下だって　お棺とこ追いたされた連中ばっかじゃないか
All our guys are men who've been
kicked out of everyplace else.
Don't talk bad about our comrades.
仲間を悪く言うな
If we keep stealing books, the Bantorra
Librarians will come eventually.
こんなだけ「本」を盗み続けてりゃ
バントーラの司書だって黙っちゃいない
Things won't go smoothly forever!
もうそううまく行かないぜ
You're free to leave on your own.
I won't stop you.
いやなら　お前一人で抜けろ　止めません
You've always been like that.
お前はがきのごろからいつもそれだ
潮時間違えるといいことないぜ
No good will come of staying
in the game too long.
お頭　どうかしたんですか？
Chief!
Is something the matter?
That should be obvious.
見りゃ　分かるだろう
You can't keep the chief waiting forever!
お前ら　お頭をいつまでも待たせんじゃないよ
すみません
My apologies.
It won't happen again.
I'm sorry, Chief.
お頭　すみませんでした
We had quite the haul today!
今日は上物が手に入ったぞ
Look! We'll sell this and
feast like kings today!
あー　これ売って今日は宴じゃ
Heave-ho.
Snuff books?
「赤本」？
Yes. I've heard rumors of
people using them lately.
最近使われている話を聞いたんだがな
Oh, because they die.
あれは「真人」が出るからね
We only sell books for porn here.
うちは掘るのしかやらないですよ
Could you let me know
if you hear anything?
何か聞いたら　知らせてくれるか
Absolutely.
分かりました
それで…　あの二人は…
By the way, those two...
Is that some sort of punishment?
何かの罰ゲーム？
So this is a black market for books.
これが闇「本」市場　下劣ですわ　お兄様
Isn't that despicable, Brother?
お前は宿に戻ってよ　ユーリ
Go back to the inn, Yuri.
Don't mind them. They're with me.
気にするな
それじゃ　わしもな
It's hot enough to make you
want to kill someone.
殺人できな暑さですわ
これ以上の捜索は物理的に無理だろう
It's physically impossible to keep the
search up under these conditions.
You'll have to relieve us, Minth.
ミンス　後は頼む
Did you think about maybe getting
some cooler clothes?
その前に　その服をどうにかしようと発想はないか
There are tons of shops around here.
その辺にいくらでも売っているぞ
Do you honestly think I'd
wear clothes sold here?
こんな町で売っている服を私が着るとでも思っているんですの？
肌を晒すのと医者に言われている
The doctor told us not to
expose our skin to the sun.
Talk about high-maintenance...
面倒じゃ
Yukizona and Yuri?
ユキゾナとユーリ？
療養中じゃなかったのか？
Aren't they undergoing medical treatment?
They get whiny if I don't give them
work every once in a while.
たまには仕事をあげないと拗ねるのよ
Also, aren't they of the nobility?
それに　あの二人が貴族の出でしょう
ガンダリみたいな町　見せておいたほうがいいかなって
I figured they should see a town like
Gandari up close and personal.
I've got a bad, bad feeling about this.
なんか　著しくいやな予感がするじゃ
So you're passing on it?
じゃ　やめる？
Hmm?
Too bad. The mission involves
retrieving some snuff books.
任務は「赤本」の回収だけど
She's so shrewd...
まったく　怖い人じゃ
Th-Th-They sell something so shameless?!
こ、こ、こんな破廉恥な…
I told you not to read it.
だから　読むなと言っただろう
この店の「本」を回収する
We're confiscating your books. Understood?
いいな
What? But you can't just...
えー　そんな　いきなり…
Hold on.
待って
えー　なんですの？
What did you say?
Our mission is to get snuff books.
わしらの目的はあくまで「赤本」じゃ
Don't do anything that could interfere.
任務に支障を来たすようなことはするな
Surely, you're not telling us
to overlook it, are you?
まさか　見過ごせというのか
How can this barbarian also
be an Armed Librarian?
こんな蛮人が同じ武装司書だなんて
Would you keep it down?
がたがたうるさいぞ
I can hear your entire conversation.
店の中まで丸聞こえだぜ
Yo, Minth!
よっ　ミンス
Who the heck are you?
なんだ　貴様
I could ask the same of you.
お前らこそなんだよ　なんかの修行か？
You on some training exercise?
Don't make me kill you.
殺しますわよ
Oh... Scary.
おー　こわ
That's enough.
そのぐらいにしておけ
本気になれば　おぬしなど一瞬で消される
If she were serious,
she'd kill you in a heartbeat.
I should expect nothing less
from an Armed Librarian, huh?
さすが武装司書ってわけですか
Okay, how about I open
my restaurant to you.
なら　持て成すとしますか
こちらへどうぞ
Please come this way.
You know this guy?
知り合いか
His name's Greihn. And sadly, I do.
グレイン　腐れんじゃ
How is it? I made the soup with crawfish,
just caught this morning.
どうだい　朝取立てのザリガニのスープだぜ
なんか　泥臭いぞ
It smells sorta muddy.
That just means it's fresh.
新鮮な証拠だよ
The cream and butter are cheap, too.
生クリームもバターンも安物だな
But it's still good, right?
でも　うまいだろう
たっく　武装司書ってな　素直じゃねえな
You Armed Librarians are really
harsh, you know that?
I'd like to partake myself.
私もいただきますわ
Yuri! You...
ユーリ　お前…
That belonged to a girl who left me,
but looks like you like it.
出てった女のやつだが　気にいってもらえたみたいだなあ
This is better than the junk
they're selling in town.
まあ　街で売られているゴミよりはましですわね
少々サイズが大きいのですが…
Though it's a bit too big.
Sure your breasts aren't too small?
胸が足りてねえだけじゃねえか
Minth, I think I'd like to kill him, after all.
ミンスさん　こちらの方やはり殺しますわね
Knock yourself out.
好きにしれ
おいおい　待ってよ
Whoa, whoa. Wait a second.
わたしができないとでも
You don't think I can do it?!
Come on. If you're wasted from
that tiny bit of booze,
おー　そのぐらいの酒で酔っ払っちまうようじゃ
任務は無理に決まっているだろう
there's no way you can complete your mission.
Drunk?
酔ってなの
Y'all are lightweights.
お主ら　酒に弱いな
I can't handle cheap alcohol...
安酒は口に合わん
やってやろうじゃありません
Shall I give it a try, then?
It's impossible. Give it up.
無理無理　止めとけ
Just you watch, you "thief."
盗賊不善が　見てるといいですわ
もし聞き出すことができたら　きちんと謝罪していただきますわ
If I'm able to get them to talk,
I'll be expecting an apology!
Oh, sounds like a bet!
おー　いいぜ
そこ　待って
You'll spin around three times
and say you're sorry.
Yuri...
You'll spin around three times
and say you're sorry.
御免なさい　いただきますわ　覚悟なさい
You'll spin around three times
and say you're sorry.
Get ready!
安心せ　いざとなったら助ける
Relax. I'll help when the time comes.
そこの方
You there.
うん？
Snuff books?
「赤本」？
Yes. I'm interested in them.
そうなの　私ちょっと興味がありまして
That's a dangerous path.
あれは危ないぜ
それにうかつなことを教えたら　俺の身だって…
And if I tell you too much,
I'll put myself in danger, too...
I'll be sure to properly thank you.
もちろん　御礼はしますわ
もし「赤本」の情報を持ってきてくれたら…
If you know anything about
the snuff books, then...
くれたら？
Then?
I'll hold your hand.
握ってさしあげますわ　あなたの手を
Bye.
じゃ
Don't get me all hot and
bothered for nothing, flatty!
変な期待させんじゃねえ　乳なしが
No one humiliates me and gets away with it!
許しませんわ　こんな屈辱
Sorry about her.
すまんの
俺たちはもう少し飲むか
Up for another drink?
What do you think?
どう思う？
Yeah. I'm pretty sure about it.
そうですわね
ほぼ間違えないと思いますわ
All right, lay down.
さあ　寝てください
Try to relax.
楽にして
A snuff book.
「赤本」だ！
見てみろよ　「赤本」だぜ
Look for yourself. It's a snuff book!
Holy crap! At the black market, they said
they'd pay a million kiluwes for one.
まじかよ
出たら　100万キルエで買取だって
闇本屋のやつ言ってただろう
Yep.
We're tossing it.
捨てるぞ
ミンス　お前馬鹿か？
Minth! What're you, stupid?!
You're the ones being stupid!
Do you know what this book is?
馬鹿はお主らじゃ
この「本」がどんな「本」か分かっているのか？
It'll make you feel incredible
if you read it, right?
読むとすげー気持ちよくなるって「本」でしょう
This isn't the record of someone's life.
これはな　人の生きた記録ではない
They're made by shattering someone's mind,
異常犯罪者の妄想　快楽殺人者の快楽の記憶
granting them to access to the
fantasies of pathological criminals,
or the euphoria a serial killer
feels when he murders.
その部分だけを　精神が破壊された一人のものに読ませ
A book deliberately created
to get people addicted.
意図的に作り上げられたまやかしの「本」じゃ
The pleasure from reading it will
slowly erode one's psyche.
読めば快楽がしだいに神経を蝕み
You'll start seeking out
the euphoria again.
再び快楽を求め
Eventually, you'll become consumed
by the book and die.
いずれ「本」に飲まれ死に至る
B-But...
で、でも…
I came here to steal books,
わしはな　「本」を盗んでは来たが
but I'd like to think I haven't
forgotten my respect for them.
「本」への敬意は忘れておらんつもりじゃ
Hey!
おーい　盗賊が今更きれい語とか
A thief suddenly has a conscious?!
待ってよ
Wait!
How many years has it been
since we've done this?
何年ぶりだ　二人でこうすんのは
Beats me.
さーな　忘れたかったからな
I had hoped to forget about it.
What on earth?
なんだと
Do they possess magic rights?
魔法権利を持っているんですの？
Stand back. I'll destroy them.
下っていろ　消滅させる
Hey.
なあ…
What's up?
なんだ？
Mind if I have a look at your soul?
お主の魂　見てもいいか？
Sorry.
悪いな
お前ら
Guys...
Nice, Greihn. I figured you'd do it.
さすがグレイン　お前ならやると思ってたぜ
Let's hurry, sell the thing,
and split the money.
とっとと売って　皆で山分けしようじゃないか
I should have known.
なるほど　こんなところに居ても
Even here... Once a scumbag,
always a scumbag, huh?
くずはくずなりに生きる知恵は持ってるってわけか
Hey, Greihn?
おーい　グレイン
How much per person?
一人いぐらだ？
I guess fifty...
No, a hundred grand.
さーな　5　いや10万ぐらいか
One hundred per person.
一人なら100だ
He really did a number on the place.
はでにやったな
I couldn't believe it.
信じられませんでしたわ
「本」を読んだだけで　あんなに…
All from merely reading a book.
「赤本」に精神を破壊された者は
When a snuff book destroys someone's psyche,
they lose their pain threshold, sense of smell,
意識どころか　痛覚や嗅覚を奪われ
and essentially turn into savage beasts.
獣のようになっていくからな
What is it?
なんだ？
か、勘弁してくださいよ
C-Cut me some slack!
Then, you'd better tell me everything
you know about the snuff books.
なら「赤本」について知ってることを正直に言え
l-I've got nothing to do with that-
だ、だから　うちは関係ない
Sorry, but I'm gonna have
to look at your soul.
すまんが　魂を見せてもらうぞ
M-My soul?
た、魂？
Stay still. It'll only take a second.
じっとしていろ　すぐ終わる
Let him go. He's telling the truth.
放せ　嘘はついておらん
Wh-Wha...
え？
Let's go.
行くぞ
Why did you lie?
なぜ嘘をつく？
Huh?
うん？
That man was hiding something.
今の男　何か隠している
You don't trust my Sacred Eyes?
わしの聖浄眼が信じられん言うんか
That's not it. You're just choosing
not to examine what you saw.
そうではない
貴様が見えたものから目を逸らしているだけだ
Just what are you getting at?
何を言い出すんかと思ったら
I'll find out if you're lying.
隠してもすぐばれるぞ
Oh, that's right.
そうですわね
今朝バントーラから届いた「本」ですわ
This book arrived this morning from Bantorra.
It's the book of someone who died
from abusing a snuff book.
「赤本」の見すぎで死んだ者の「本」
Reading this will clarify who hooked them on it.
これを読めば　誰が読ませていたのか
はっきりしますわ
I don't need to read it.
読むまでもない
すまんかったの　武装司書になった時
I'm sorry.
I thought I had abandoned stuff like this
once I became an Armed Librarian.
こういうのを捨てたつもりでいたんだが
Minth?
ミンスさん
Go back and get something to eat.
戻って飯でも食べておれ
I'll go get the snuff book.
「赤本」はわしが持ってる
Greihn, please! Greihn!
グレイン　頼むよ　グレイン
A little bit! I just need to read it once more!
ちょっといいんだよ
どうしてももう一度読みたいんだよ
One million.
100万だ
I don't have that kind of money!
無理だよ　最初はただで読ませてくれたじゃないかよ
You let me read it for free the first time!
How much do you have?
いくらある？
This is all I've got.
これで　頼む
You get to read it, not to keep it.
読むだけだぞ
うん？
What are you doing here so late?
どうした　こんな時間に
An Armed Librarian reading porn?
武装司書がポルノかよ
いや　ただの「本」じゃ
Nope, merely a regular book.
The book of a man who died
from abusing a snuff book.
「赤本」を読んで死んだ男の
It's not like you.
お主らしくないな
You should have known this
would happen someday...
死んだ人間が「本」として残る可能性がある以上
That it'd be left in their
books when they died.
いずれこうなることは予想できたじゃろう
Why didn't you rush to sell it?
なぜとっとと売り払わなかった
I found by getting people
hooked on snuff books,
売るよりも儲かるんだよ　「赤本」の虜にさせたほうがな
I could make more than by selling them.
罪を重ねて手に入れたのがこんな小さな店か
And this tiny restaurant was
all you got for your sins.
I thought about it every day...
毎日思ってたよな
Starting a new life down below,
何時か下で生活してやるってな
eating soup with a silver spoon.
銀のスプーンでスープを飲んでやるってな
But I went up a mountain when
I had planned to climb down.
なのに　下に降りるどころか山に昇っちまった
Who would do such a thing?
誰がこんなことを
I lied to you,
お前騙して　仲間殺して
killed our comrades,
and got the snuff book.
「赤本」手に入れて　やっと降りてきた
Then I finally came down.
Now, if I want, I can eat buckets
of soup with a silver spoon.
今じゃ銀のスプーンでバケツいっぱいのスープを食らえる
But that's not it.
だが　違うんだよ
This isn't the world I so desired from afar!
ここはいつも指くわえてみてた　あの世界じゃない
Things haven't improved since coming here.
ここにいった　あの頃と変わらない
いや　あの頃よりもっと遠くなっちまった
No, I've gotten even farther away from it.
Greihn...
グレイン
So what should I do, Minth?
なあ　ミンス
どうすりゃいい？
店をでかくすりゃ近づけるのか？
Think expanding this place will bring me closer?
Highly doubt it, huh?
そうじゃねえだろう
Answer me! How much more money do I need?!
教えてくれよ　後どれだけ金が必要だ？
Tell me! What should I do
to make it down below?!
なあ　どうすりゃ俺は下に降りられるんだよ
Looks like you need our help after all, huh?
とてもお任せできる状況にありませんね
Yukizona... Yuri.
ユキゾナ　ユーリ
So, you came.
やはり来たか
Get them!
やれ！
Not gonna happen!
無駄だ
この町をふっ飛ばしてもいいぞ
I'll blow the whole town apart if I have to.
Greihn.
グレイン
I'll never be satisfied,
no matter how much money I get
いくら金が入っても　町にいても
or how long I stay in this town.
満足一つねえ
This wasn't worth it at all.
まったく割りにあわねえよな
All that awaits me is a lifetime of regret.
それなのに　後悔だけは襲ってくれ
I'll keep blaming myself forever.
自分を責める声だけは聞こえて来る
You wouldn't understand...
お前には分らんか
You think not?
そう見えるか
わしはな
Actually,
I thought long and hard about
selling that book.
その「本」を金に換えようかと迷っておった
Just like you did...
お主と同じようにな
So, when our comrades died,
part of me thought,
だから仲間が死んだとき　どこかで思ってしまったじゃ
"I'm saved."
助かったと
"I can leave this place now without
having to commit any sins."
これでわしは何の罪を背負うこともなく
ここを去ることができると
ミンス
Minth...
I've peered into the souls of countless
men with my Sacred Eyes.
わしはな　この聖浄眼で今まで無数の人間を見てきた
Not a single one of them were without sin.
じゃがな　ただ一人として罪を纏わぬ魂はない
Don't you find that funny?
笑えると思えんか
Committing sins to escape sins
you've already committed...
罪から逃れるために罪を重ね
By the time you realize it,
you've lost sight of it, buried in your sins...
気がつけば　罪の中に埋もれて
見失ってしまうんじゃ　自分は何を求めていたのか
Lost sight of what you were
after in the first place.
Wow! This is great!
うめぇ　グレインさんの主厨最高すよ
Your stew is the best, Greihn!
だろう
Isn't it?
あー　俺の分まで食いやがって
Hey! You didn't save any for me!
お前ら　がっつきすぎだぞ
Damn vultures!
これなら　店出せるじゃないか
You should open up a restaurant, man.
That's a great idea! I'd definitely eat there.
いいすね　俺らうりつめますよ
No other customers would get near
the place with you guys there.
お前らみたいのがいたんじゃ　ほかの客が寄り近ないづーの
That's it...
そうか　俺が降りてきたかった憧れてた世界は
The world I had so admired
and wanted to descend to
doesn't exist anymore.
もうどこにもねえんだな
I forced you to bear the burden of
killing our companions alone.
お主だけに仲間殺しの罪を背負わせた
And now...
今度は　わしがその罪を背負う
I will bear it for you.
Thank you, partner...
ありがとうよ　相棒
The ultimate transient happiness.
究極の仮初めの幸福　お気に召しますかどうか
I wonder if you'll like it.
Seems they do.
気に入ったみたいね
So, what happened with Minth?
で　どうだったの？　ミンスは
As you had pointed out,
there were far too many problems.
代行が指摘されたように　あまりにも問題が多い
However...
ですが
Hmm?
彼はすべての状況を受け入れる
He accepts the entirety of the circumstances.
He possesses both weakness and strength.
強さと弱さを持ってますわ
そうね
That's true.
それが一番大切なことかもね
That might be the most important thing...
楽園管理者には
For the Governor of Paradise.
Taiyo tojiru mae ni
Hikari wo nakushite
Mekurumeku arashi nara
Temaneku mae ni tobikomu
Dare mo itsuka owaru no deshou
Sono hi ga kureba
Mawaridasu mirai wo mezashite
Tada sore wa mou shirusarete ita to shitemo
Sagashidasu kizutsuku imi sae kono te ni
Jibunrashiku aru tame ni
A Return Home,
A boy becomes a man,
少年は青年となり
and walks down a road from
which he can never return.
二度と戻れぬ道を歩き出す
A Return Home, an Encounter,
and walks down a road from
which he can never return.
A girl becomes a woman,
少女は女となり
and softly steps on the boy's
shadow, as he leaves.
去り行く青年の影を そっと踏む
A Return Home, an Encounter,
and Burning Bridges
and softly steps on the boy's
shadow, as he leaves.
归来与相逢和燃烧之绿
and softly steps on the boy's
shadow, as he leaves.